Bryan Ortiz - Data Scientist

(515) 490-7304 | ortizbryan54321@gmaill.com | Des Moines, IA | Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

As an aspiring Data Scientist, I am skilled in Python, SQL, Data Visualization, and Machine Learning, with a strong background in Neuroscience. I am passionate about leveraging data-driven insights to solve complex problems and thrive on collaborating with teams to tackle challenging data projects.

SKILLS

- Languages: Python (scikit learn, pandas, etc), R, SQL, and Spanish;
- Data Visualization: Seaborn, Matplotlib
- Supervised / Unsupervised Machine Learning
- Natural Language Processing

PROJECTS

Ames, IA Housing Price Prediction

• Analyzed housing prices from Ames, IA via linear regression to create a predictive model for sales prices of future listings, with 89% accuracy.

Web APIs & NLP

 Developed an accurate post classifier for the psychedelic community using data from Reddit, providing valuable insights into topics, discussions, and experiences with an 87% accuracy score, contributing to the understanding of human consciousness and psychedelic exploration.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Science Fellow, General Assembly | Remote

May 2023 - Aug. 2023

• 12-week, 400+ hour training program focusing on the ability to analyze, make sense of, convey data-driven facts from massive data sets, and predict what happens next through predictive modeling and pattern recognition

Loan Documentation Specialist 2, Wells Fargo | Des Moines, IA

July 2020 - Nov. 2021

- Analyzed an average of 50 home loans per day for data inaccuracies and inconsistencies
- Drove positive impacts on customers' lives by ensuring home loan data timeliness and integrity
- Communicated lienholders to obtain accurate loan and customer data to enter into CORE and OPS

Personal Trainer and Nutritionist, LifeTime Athletic | Des Moines, IA

July 2019 - July 2020

- Cultivated \$6,000 in sales per month within first 6 months
- Achieved a 95% retention rate reached by building rapport with 20 consistent clients
- Maintained accurate, detailed and up-to-date online records of client and training data

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY | REMOTE

Data Science Immersive - Certificate

Expected Aug 2023

University of Iowa | Iowa City, IA

B.S. Neuroscience

Member of Acacia Fraternity

May 2019

CERTIFICATIONS

- CompTIA A+
- CompTIA Network+
- CompTIA Security+
- MultiCloud Aviatrix Associate